Top Gear 第18季 第1集
字幕制作: 百度TopGear吧 derekdi 清野过客 吃烧饼不掉芝麻
水平有限 难免有误 敬请谅解
非常感谢. 大家好!
Thank you so much. Hello!
大家晚上好,感谢光临!
Hello and welcome. Thank you, everybody. Thank you.
尽管最近以来这档节目在各种媒体上的声誉不高
Now, even though this programme has taken a
terrible battering in the newspapers in recent weeks and months,
我们已经尽最大的努力使这个季度不受舆论影响
we have made every effort we possibly can
to make sure this series is unaffected.
诚挚感谢大家
Thank you. Thank you, really.
谢谢
Thanks very much.
那么接下来就是一段以下七周节目的精彩内容剪辑
So, coming up now is a montage of
what you can expect over the next seven weeks.
每加仑57英里! (约等于百公里4升)
57 miles to the gallon!
结论是,空间大,而且经济实惠
So, spacious...and economical.
转过第一弯..
Going through the first corner...
这就是凸轮轴的工作原理
And THAT is how a camshaft works.
老兄!
Mate!
不对!! 放错了
No-o-o! There's been a bit of a mistake.
那是给报纸媒体们送去的剪辑
为了蛊惑他们认为我们从良了
THAT is the tape we sent to the newspapers
in the hope they'd be fooled into thinking
我们真正要放的剪辑是这个!
that's what we'll be doing.
What we're actually doing is THIS!
不妙! 我不想在后视镜里看见那个!
Oh, no! That's not what I wanted to see in the mirror!
来到轮胎墙..
Heading to the tyres...
他在那儿! 他在那儿!!
There he is! There he is!
左转进入阿卡西亚大街
(注:"阿卡西亚大街"是英国中产阶级的象征)
Turning left into Acacia Avenue.
在那边,在那边! 往那里开!!
Over there. Over there. Go over there!
他是Stig的中国表兄
He's The Stig's Chinese cousin.
稳住你的脊椎
Hold onto your spine.
约翰逊的起步很出色
Johnson makes a good start.
快开啊,你个老破玩意儿!
Come on, you little bugger!
天呐,这里能抓到不少好镜头
Man alive! Are we getting some shots here?!
不好意思,我只是打酱油的
Thank you. Just browsing.
努力,努力,努力! 加油!!
Stretch it, stretch it, stretch it!
Come on!
那怎么可能?!
How's that possible?
干的太漂亮了
Oh... That was beautiful.
那些内容都即将播出,不过我们今晚从它说起
All of that is to come,
but we kick off tonight with this.
没错,因为这个很重要
Yes, because this is important.
比方说,你想要一辆中置引擎的超级跑车
Let's say you want a mid-engine supercar
不过出于某种原因,你不想要法拉利458
but, for some reason, you don't want a Ferrari 458.
那么你应该选哪辆呢?
What is best for you?
毫无疑问的是,我们仨不能达成共识
Now, naturally, of course,
us three could not agree on a solution on this,
所以制片人让我们用一次横跨意大利的路试来一决高下
so the producer said we had to settle
our differences with a road trip across Italy.
我们的聚集点是美丽的莱切城,它位于亚平宁之靴的足根处
'The meeting point was the beautiful
town of Lecce, in the heel of Italy,
我是第一个到的
'and I was the first to arrive.'
这就是迈凯轮MP4-12C
This is the McLaren MP4-12C.
它对于细节的追求简直令人发指
It's a car made with an almost
psychotic attention to detail.
它非常高科技,所以我觉得它会很适合我
It's very technical. It's why, I think,
it probably suits me quite well.
然后杰里米开着一辆很适合他的车到了
Then Jeremy arrived in a car
that suits HIM quite well.
早上好,"低调君"
Morning, shrinking violet.
这个嘛..
This...
就是兰博基尼Aventador了
..is a Lamborghini Aventador.
关于这车我最喜欢的一点是
奥迪揽了引擎啊电线啊这些无趣的活儿
What I love most of all about this is that
Audi did all the boring engine and wiring bits
而留给兰博基尼在造型上耍宝
and then let Lamborghini go mad with the styling.
造型上比你的强得多,于是它就是更好
It looks better than yours and,
therefore, it IS better.
没错. 作为一直以来的海报尤物,兰博基尼一直处于顶尖
I agree. As a poster,
as Lamborghinis always have been, it is superb.
外形让人无话可说
It looks great.
不过老实说,这车长的有点恐龙了
But it's a bit of a dinosaur, to be honest.
-它太大,太宽..  -你说啥?!
-这辆车,你看上去就知道..
It's too big, it's too wide. I'm sorry?!
This, you just know...
这辆车的工程师张口闭口就谈G力. 他们就坐在那儿
All they ever talked about was G.
They were sitting going,
"我们怎么能让这辆车过弯再快一点?"
"How can we make it go round
a corner a little bit faster?"
-它是辆超跑!  -对啊! 给它配枪吧! 再装上个火箭吧!
It's a supercar. "So give it guns!
Let's give it guns! Space rockets!"
看这个,它们估计开了7年的会议来决定雨刷器的造型
This - they will have had seven years of meetings
to get to that windscreen wiper.
-所以它能够工作正常,这又有什么错?
-兰博基尼工程师会说, "我们为啥不用激光?"
So it works properly. What's wrong with that?
Lamborghini would've said, "Why don't we use a laser?
"我们为啥不用激光往玻璃上喷热气?"
"Why don't we have lasers shooting
heat onto the windscreen to...?"
-这才是我热爱兰博的原因,它们头脑疯狂!
-你今天汽水喝多了吧?!
That's why I love Lambos. They're mental.
Have you had a lot of pop today?
这时候,哈蒙德开了一辆Noble M600到达了
'At that moment, Hammond arrived, in a Noble M600.'
-哈蒙德..  -早上好
-让我们搞搞清楚
So, Hammond... Morning.
Let's just get this straight.
你还真觉得这世界上有人会想
You think there are people
in the world who are going to say,
"恩,我不想要一辆异国的意大利跑车,不要法拉利"
"No, I don't want something Italian and exotic.
Don't want a Ferrari.
"我想要一辆莱切斯特轻工业工棚里造出来的东西"
I want something built on a light industrial
unit in Leicestershire."
等等,我觉得你买这辆车的唯一原因就是
它的引擎来自于沃尔沃XC90
No, wait a minute. Sorry. You buy this, I think,
because it's got the engine from a Volvo XC90.
没错,它的引擎确实是沃尔沃引擎,不过是雅马哈制造的
No! Yes, the engine may be from
a Volvo, but it's made by Yamaha.
匹配卓越的双引擎,而且更出色的是,这辆车很轻
It's twin-engine, it's absolutely magnificent,
and this car, above everything else, is light.
这就像是 拿我和你比较
Comparing these - it's like comparing me with you.
它的马力重量比例很疯狂 - 每吨541匹马力
The power-to-weight ratio is insane.
541 brake horsepower per tonne in there.
那已经可以和布加迪威龙相提并论了,这你是知道的!
That's Bugatti Veyron territory, and you know it!
用这辆车击败你们肯定就像碾过甲壳虫一样容易
This is going to crush you guys
like beetles under its feet.
很快,我们的跑车吸引了一群闲杂人等..
Soon, our cars started to draw a bit of a crowd...
于是制片人让我们出城,并在乡下撒撒欢
..so the producer said we should leave the town
and go for a little drive in the country.
老天爷啊!
Bloody hellfire!
不赖
Quite good.
你也许在坐下心想,"为什么我要花22万8千英镑"
You are probably sitting there, thinking,
"Hold on! Why would I spend 228,000 pounds
"买一辆莱切斯特造的,没有气囊和ABS的跑车?"
"on a car with no airbags or
anti-lock brakes, made in Leicester?"
不过这不是重点
But that's missing the point.
如果我问另外那两人,历史上最棒的超级跑车是哪一辆
If I were to ask those two what the
best supercar ever made is,
我能猜到他们的答案
I know what they'd answer.
法拉利F40
Ferrari F40.
这辆车就含有那种"法拉利F40主义"
There's something of the Ferrari F40 about this.
这与它的驾乘感受有很大的关系
Something to do with the way it rides on the road,
the way it feels.
也许是它的简约使其如此卓越
The simplicity of it.
我知道超跑一般都会很花哨,这点我清楚
I buy the argument for a flamboyant supercar.
I get it.
不过也许就有另外一种风格
But maybe there is another way of doing it.
当每个部件都工作出色时,你能感到这种乐趣
就像这个变速箱一样
There's a sort of joy in things that simply
work really well, like this gearbox.
这就像是狙击枪上的二阶式扳机
It's sort of like a two-stage
trigger on a sniping rifle -
你先用一半的弹药来预载,然后再切换
you can preload it with half a ball...
and then change.
我非常满意
It's very satisfying.
也许对细节的追求能使得它有自己的一番天地,我们走着瞧
Maybe really anal attention to detail
will have a charm of its own. Let's see.
詹姆斯和理查德可以爱怎么说怎么说,不过事实是不变的
James and Richard can make as many arguments
as they want, but the fact is this.
他们俩开的就像是维珍可乐
(注:类似中国的"非常可乐")
They're driving about in Virgin Cola.
那些都是山寨的. 这个才是实在货
It's not the real thing. This is the real thing.
兰博基尼用缪拉开创了超跑天地
Lamborghini invented the supercar with the Miura,
缪拉是史上首辆中置引擎的速度梦想机器
the world's first mid-engine speed and dream machine.
确实,这辆车是这三辆里面最贵的
I mean, yes, this is the most expensive car here.
它要25万英镑,不过谁会管它的售价呢?
这是辆梦中坐骑
A quarter of a million pounds.
But who cares? It's a dream car.
你才不会梦想着去费雷城或是去布雷德灵顿(英国城市)
你会梦想着去大溪地度假
You don't dream about going to Filey or Bridlington.
You dream about going to Tahiti.
话说回来,大溪地相当差劲. 我去了一次
Actually, Tahiti's terrible. I went there once.
那里全都是对着海豚发呆的美国佬
It was full of Americans looking at dolphins.
半小时后,有人告诉我们要去加油
'Half an hour later, we were told to
brim the tanks in our cars
并仔细听好我们即将接受的挑战
'and pay careful attention to the
challenge we were about to receive.'
"你们现在要看看哪辆车极速最快"
"You will now see which of
your cars can achieve the highest speed."
多简单,一定是我的了
That'll be mine. It's as simple as that.
它的极速最高
It's the fastest.
"不过这和你们的车的极速无关."
"How fast your car can go is not relevant."
"而和你们敢开多快有关"
"It's how fast you dare drive it."
这个挑战的地点是纳多测试赛道
'The location for this challenge
was the Nardo test track,
一个全长8英里的柏油圆形跑道
它的面积非常大,从太空都能清楚地看的见
'a banked 8-mile circle of tarmac
so vast it can be seen clearly from space.
没有车能够在这里达到理论极速
因为整条赛道是个无尽的弯道
'No car can achieve its true top speed here
because it's one endless corner.
不过能让车接近于它的理论极速的地方
除了这里,世界上也只有两三个了
'But it is one of only two or three
places in the world where they can get close.
兰博基尼和迈凯轮都派出了技术人员
'Lamborghini and McLaren had
both sent technicians to make sure their cars,
来确保跑车,尤其是轮胎,能够经受住长期高速转弯的热量
'and especially the tyres, could handle
the vast heat of constant high-speed cornering.
不过对于理查德和他莱切斯特的跑车来说..
'But as for Richard and his car from Leicester...'
-Noble在这里没有保修厂吗?  -保修厂,没有
Do Noble not have a workshop here?
Not a workshop, no.
如果我们在马洛里赛道上做的话,他们能送个工程师来吧!
(马洛里赛道位于Noble总部的莱斯特郡)
I suppose if we were doing this
at Mallory Park, they'd send Geoff over(!)
我开过他,没问题. 四个轮胎都在
I've done it. It's all right.
All four tyres are the same makes.
轮胎也有气
That there's air in 'em.
詹姆斯和我感觉信心满满
'James and I were feeling fairly confident...
不过当我们和一位兰博基尼试车手,马克思・凡度里,聊天时
'until we started chatting to
a man called Max Venturi,
我们的自信消失了
'who is one of Lambo's test drivers.'
我们在这里做很多赛道测试,不过不经常测试极速
We do a lot of testing here but
we don't do too much the top speed,
因为赛道很颠
because it is very bumpy.
你都能从一条车道弹跳到另一条车道上去
You...you could jump from one lane to the other lane,
听起来不太妙啊
so is... That sounds bad.
而且今天风很大
And also, today, it is windy,
-你们也要小心风
-那么我们需要抢风调向么(帆船用语)?
so you need to take care about the wind, as well.
What, do we need to tack(?)
因为速度表不是完全准确
'Because speedometers are never absolutely accurate,
制片人在我们的车上装配了高科技遥感设备
'the producers fitted each
of our cars with hi-tech telemetry
所以他们会测出我们的速度
'so they could see how fast we were really going.
之后我们上了赛道,开了几圈暖胎圈
'And then we were sent on to
the track for a sighting lap.'
在这里我有最多的本钱能输掉
I have the most to lose here.
理论上我的车极速最高 - 225英里每小时
(约为360公里每小时)
My car is the fastest - top speed 225mph.
杰里米的兰博极速217, (约为349公里每小时)
詹姆斯的迈凯轮极速是205. (约为330公里每小时)
Jeremy's Lambo - 217, James's McLaren 205mph,
迈凯轮已经慢到了散步的速度
or to put it another way, a walking pace.
我的引擎有691匹马力
Now, I have 691 brake horsepower at my disposal.
比詹姆斯的足足多了100匹
That's almost 100 more than James has.
而且我的是纯纯正正的马力
And it's proper horsepower.
真正的贵族纯种
Blue-blooded, real horsepower.
托尾气排放新规的福
Thanks to emission regulations,
这辆车的V12引擎可能是世界上最后的一台了
this is probably the last V12 engine
that will ever be made.
从现在开始,引擎一律要更小,并要加装涡轮增压
From now on, they'll have to be
smaller and turbo charged,
就像Noble的和迈凯轮的一样
like they are in the Noble and the McLaren.
的确,我的引擎最小,只是台3.8升V8引擎
Yes, my engine is the smallest. It's a 3.8-litre V8,
不过它的输出比量最大,在所有这三台引擎中
but it has the highest specific output,
that is, of all the engines here,
每升排气量,它能产出最多的马力值
it produces the most BHP per litre,
因为这台引擎是被沃金的工程师们精心调教出的
because it's been intelligently
designed by engineers in Woking,
而不是拼凑在一起为了取悦蛮人
not just put together to impress yahoos.
那两个人不断地说这台引擎来自于沃尔沃XC90
Those two keep banging on about,
"This has got the engine out of a Volvo XC90."
是,没错,不过不要忘了,引擎制造商是雅马哈
Yes, well, OK, but let's not forget, Yamaha make it,
雅马哈曾经造过许多卓越的摩托车引擎
and they produce some pretty
amazing motorcycle engines,
之后Noble又装了两个涡轮,结果就是它能产出650匹马力
and Noble have then strapped
two turbos to it, so it makes 650 brake horsepower.
话是那么说,马力是可变的
I say that, but I can change that.
按下这个按钮,我可以使用"公路模式"的450匹马力
或是"赛道模式"的550匹马力
With this button down here,
I can have 450 for road, 550 for track,
或者"狂飙模式"的650匹.
今天我就用它完完整整的650匹马力吧
or 650 for race.
I'm going to have the full 650, I think, today.
我还是对小矮个儿敢做这个测试感到由衷的敬佩的
I do have quite a lot of respect for
the Midget doing this, because...
因为上一次他在赛道上挑战极速时,情况不太妙
(第9季第1集理查德驾驶喷气赛车爆胎重伤)
Well, the last time he tried to go fast
on a test track, it didn't go well.
暖胎圈结束
With the sighting lap over,
我们被告知拉开距离,放手去开
we were told to put some distance
between ourselves and go for it.
转到最外线
I'm moving up into the outside lane.
时速250公里
It's 250kph.
现在我们在第6档上
Now we're in 6th speed...
小爬坡
Moving up a little bit...
确实有点振动,感觉不爽
It does feel a bit wobbly. I don't like it.
270...
亲娘啊,这赛道表面太差劲了!
My God, this surface is shocking!
风来了! 振动感来了!
There's the wind! There's the wobble!
车身弹跳!
There's the jump!
天啊!!
Ooh, God!
现在是280公里每小时,车身晃动得厉害了. 290..
See, that is 280,
and it's really starting to weave now. 290...
兰博基尼试车手马克思警告我们说
'Max from Lamborghini had warned all of us
开过时速300公里太危险了
'that it would be too dangerous
to exceed 300km per hour.
不过我们都忽略了这个警告
'And all of us chose to ignore him.'
我的脚正死死地踩着
My foot is hard down now.
时速300公里..天啊!!
300 and... Oh, crikey! Moses.
要松下油门喘口气了. 吓了一大跳
I'd a lift there. Bit of a panic.
速度表上说时速300公里,我能感受到车身弹跳
300km per hour indicated.
I can feel the car jumping.
在加速! 加速!
Buffeting! Buffeting!
要吓人了..哇哦!!
There's a scare? Whoa-ho-ho!
314...316...
我的每一条神经都想让我松油门!
And every fibre of my being wants me to lift off!
我那没死去的亲娘呀!!
Oh, God Almighty!
天知道那些轮胎过的是怎样的苦日子
God knows what those tyres are going through.
这太催眠了
God, it's hypnotic.
不要看白线,不要看白线
Don't look at the line,
don't look at the line.
加油!
Come on!
再快10公里吧!! 求你啦!
Please, just another ten!
时速326!
326 indicated!
327!
327 indicated.
时速329!! 加油! 330!
329 indicated! Come on - 330!
331.
加油啊,让我比330再快一点吧!!
Come on, give me a bit more than 330!
再快一点!!
Just give me a bit more!
快一点!!
A bit more!
太他娘的快啦!!
This is BLEEP quick!
我爽够了
I'm backing out of this.
这太..
That is...
太TM吓人了..
..pretty bloody alarming.
极速测试结束,现在要看看我们三个人
'With the test over,
it was now time to find out which one of us
谁的时速最高..
'had the biggest testes.'
-你的车的理论极速是时速225英里  -没错
The top speed of your car is 225mph.
Yes.
你开到了时速204.8英里
You achieved 204.8.
-你手里是谁的成绩?  -这是詹姆斯的成绩
-詹姆斯的?  -没错
Who have you got?
I've got James's. James's? Yes.
极速最慢的一辆车. 时速二百..
In the slowest car, in the slowest car.
200... Oh!
零一点六英里
..and 1.6.
兰博基尼的极速是217英里每小时
217mph IS the top speed of the Lamborghini.
你开到了..
You did it at
204.3
好的,我们一会儿继续影片
Right, we will, of course be picking
that up again later on.
我只想说,只差了时速半英里? 我们俩只差那么多
Can I just say, half a mile an hour? That's all
there was in it between you and me. Yeah.
-如果我把油门再踩得死一点..  -是啊,不过你还是输了!
If I'd just kept my foot down...
Yeah. But you lost!
-慢着,我觉得你们俩都输了  -你什么意思?
Hold on a minute. Hold on. I think you'll find
you both lost. How did you work that out?
我的实际速度和我的理论极速最接近
Because I got closest to
the theoretical top speed of my car,
-所以我的胆子最大  -搞什么!
and therefore I have the biggest testes. No!
挑战内容是谁能开得最快,而我开得最快
The challenge was to see who could
drive the fastest, and I did.
之后我们重新加油来测算谁的耗油量最低
Then we refilled the cars, we brimmed them,
to see which had used the least fuel doing it,
想猜猜吗? 兰博的油耗是每加仑7英里 (百公里33升)
and guess what?! Well, the Lambo did 7mpg,
迈凯轮每加仑8英里, (百公里29升)
而Noble是每加仑9英里! (百公里26升)
the McLaren did 8mpg and the Noble did 9!
Noble再下一城!
So the Noble wins AGAIN! I know!
总结一下比赛成果,目前两项挑战
Let's just...just to work out where we are,
so that's two challenges so far,
Noble两战全胜,而兰博..
two wins for the Noble, and for the Lambo...
-我们看看..  -别看了,我们做新闻吧
Now, let's see. Let's not see.
Let's do the news. All right.
在新闻之前,观看了我们圣诞特辑的观众们
Actually, before that, those of you
who saw our Christmas special
可能会记得我们把三辆车留在了喜马拉雅山脉的三个底座上
will remember we left our three cars
on plinths high in the Himalayas
就在中印公路之间
on a road between China and India,
意图是为在这两个经济大国间穿行的人们
so that people passing between these
two great economic superpowers
能够永远铭记大不列颠的荣耀
would forevermore be
reminded of Great Britain.
不幸的是
Well, unfortunately,
我们建的三个底座的地方
it turns out that the plinths were built on
是一个古代陵墓
an ancient burial ground
而且有着巨大的宗教价值
with deep religious significance,
所以有位老兄马上让我们把底座拆了下来
so a man came and told us
to take them down immediately.
-于是我们照做了  -那三辆车现在在哪里?
Yeah. So we did. Where are the cars now?
-不在喜马拉雅  -那它们在那儿?
They're not in the Himalayas. But where are they?
-在汉普郡  -真的啊?
-没错,保留在那里了. 不管怎样,让我们做新闻吧
Hampshire. Really?
Yes. That's where it is. Anyway, the news.
这周的报纸报道,有位老兄驾驶理论考试挂了92次
There was a man in the papers this week who
has failed his driving theory test 92 times.
-92次?!   -我不想太粗鲁,不过这仁兄没比白痴强哪儿去吧
92?! I don't want to be rude, but he must be an idiot...
-话虽然那么说,你见过理论考试吗?
-我考驾照的时候不需要考理论
Interestingly, you say that. Have you seen
the theory test? I didn't have to do one.
这里有人参加过驾驶理论考试吗? 你参加过?
Has anyone here seen the theory test?
Anybody? Yeah. You have?
我们这辈人基本都不需要理论考试
Because most people of our age haven't,
在我看来,这些理论考试题都和"驾驶"没什么关系
and none of the questions have anything to do -
as far as I can work out - with driving.
举个例子,试着回答这个问题
Can I give you some examples? You can answer this.
"一个老年人.."
"An elderly person...
"一个老年人的能力可能被影响,因为他们无法____?"
"An elderly person's ability could be affected
because they may be unable to...?"
-无法嚼动太妃糖.  -不对
Eat toffees. No.
无法勃起
Get an erection.
无法穿牛仔裤
Wear jeans!
玩去. "在晚上最安全的停车位是哪里?"
Funny(!) "Where's the safest place
to park your vehicle at night?"
警察局
In a police station.
我们有这个照片,请把它打在屏幕上
Right, we've got a picture here.
Bring up this picture. Right.
这是道真实的考题,是吧?
This is a real question, OK?
前方学校 保持道路畅通
"在这个标志前请不要停车"
"You must not stop on these road markings
"因为你可能会堵塞_____的道路?"
"because you may obstruct...what?"
-堵塞飞机起降么?!  -不开玩笑,这是道真正的问题
Landing aircraft(!)
I mean, seriously, that is a question.
-这种问题他居然都能挂掉92次
-这些都跟开车没关系的啊!
He's managed to fail 92 times on that one.
Those are not questions to pass your driving...
有没有问题说,比如说,你会不会开车?
Do any of them say, for instance, can you drive a car?
我看的这本书是青少年驾驶教程
I'm in the book now. This is what you buy
your teenage child when they're learning to drive.
"在一起事故中,一名儿童停止了呼吸"
"At an incident, a small child is not breathing.
"要恢复正常呼吸,你需要______地向他嘴里吹气
A.急剧地 B.柔和地"
"To restore normal breathing, you should breathe
into their mouth, A sharply, B gently,
"C.大量地 D.温和地"
"C heavily, D tenderly?"
才不会是"温和地"!!
It doesn't say "tenderly"!
D那个选项是我瞎编的,不过这都跟开车没关系!
驾照考试的这一套说得够多了
I made "tenderly" up. Nothing to do with driving!
That's enough driving test rubbish.
必须要继续节目了,否则在这侃大山能侃上一整天
We'll have to move it on, or we'll be here all day.
重回到车的话题上. 话说阿尔法罗密欧
Let's talk about cars again,
because the mighty Alfa Romeo,
原来上上下下的各种车款
they are reduced now, to a full range of cars,
-现在减产到了只剩下两款. 只有两款车
-真的? 那剩下什么了, Mito和什么..?
they make two. Two cars.
Really? What, the Mito and...
-Mito和Giulietta  -那么159已经停产了吗?
The Giulietta and the Mito.
They don't make the 159 any more?
没有了,只有两款阿尔法罗密欧在产
No, two Alfa Romeos on the market,
不过情况要改变了,因为他们刚刚发布了这一款4C
but that's about to change as they
have just announced this, the 4C.
您看! 的确,它很小,轻量化的跑车
I know. It's tiny, it's a small,
lightweight sports car.
车重很轻,有碳纤维和其它各种高科技玩意儿
Very lightweight. Carbon fibre,
all sorts of clever technical stuff.
中置引擎. 它的引擎只有1.75升,不过有涡轮增压
Mid-engined, it's only a 1750CC engine,
but it's turbo charged,
由于车轻,它肯定跑得不慢. 造型更是无限华美
so it will be quick, because it's so light.
It looks fantastic!
这车做错了. 阿尔法罗密欧应该制造的车
It's wrong, is what it is.
What Alfa Romeo should make
应该是小敞篷单排跑车
is a small convertible two-seater,
前置引擎,后轮驱动
engine at the front, rear-wheel drive.
-名字应该叫做.. -Spider? (阿尔法经典车名)
-Spider这名字就很不错
They could call it, I don't know, the...
Spider? Spider's a great name.
也许他们可以找来达斯汀・霍夫曼在电影里驾驶一辆
And maybe they could get Dustin
Hoffman to appear in a film with it,
来提高它的知名度
to etch it into the world's consciousness.
阿尔法也许可以留存在记忆中
They could, they could live in the past.
不过他们选择了跟随现代的脚步并造出了这个
Or they could make something modern and
forward-looking, like that. No, rubbish!
当阿尔法罗密欧造出老Spider的时候
What if you two had been at Alfa Romeo when
如果你们俩在阿尔法能是什么样?
they came up with the original Spider?
"太差劲了,前面的马呢?"
"That's no good! Where's the horse in front of it?
-"这不是木质的,质量肯定不行"
-这才不是跟时代接轨,这是残次品
"It's not wood. That'll never work."
It's not modern. It won't work.
把它撤下去,因为我有更有兴趣的新闻
Make it go away. I've got something
more important to talk about.
新款玛莎拉蒂上市了. 这是新款的玛莎拉蒂4x4越野车,是吧?
A new Maserati. Really(?) OK.
This is the new Maserati 4x4, OK?
它看上去很漂亮,不过有些事情很奇怪
I think it looks fantastic but there
are some odd things about it.
玛莎拉蒂声称,与其它大4x4越野车不同的是
玛莎拉蒂越野车有一种奢华的气氛
Maserati say that, unlike any other
big 4x4, it has a luxury atmosphere.
因为每次我坐进路虎的驾驶舱里时,我总会想
Cos every time I get in a Range Rover,
I always think, "Oh, no!
"哦,不! 我是不是进了牛棚里了?!"
"I've accidentally got into a cowshed."
玛莎拉蒂还说
And then they say,
"没有越野车具有运动感"
"There are no off-roaders that give a sporty feel."
-保时捷卡宴? 梅赛德斯ML63?  -宝马X5?
What about the Porsche Cayenne?
Or the Mercedes ML63? BMW X5?
那些都有运动感啊
All of those?
玛莎拉蒂可能就是那种公司
I think Maserati... they're the sort of company
他们会说, "我们发明出了一种新表"
that go, "We've invented a new type of watch.
"这种表的特别之处就是你可以把它戴在手腕上!"
"What makes it really good is,
you can wear it on your wrist!"
这就麻烦了,因为必须要有勇士跟他们说
This is quite awkward, because somebody'll have
"嘿,玛莎拉蒂,有人已经做过了!"
to tell them, "Hey, Maserati, it's been done!"
我特别钟爱的一点是
What I love about this, though, is it's
它的名字叫"库班"
继承着玛莎拉蒂的优良传统
called the Kubang, which, being a Maserati,
这名字一定是保修期过期时车会发出的声音!
is the noise it'll make
the day the warranty runs out!
我们收到了一位想上电视的老兄的新闻稿
We received a press release from someone who wanted to
get their name on the television, I've always said.
他说当我们感冒的时候,我们的驾驶水平降低
Now, they say that the standard of your driving
gets worse if you're suffering from a cold.
问题是,他还说吃感冒药也不行
The thing is, they go on to say that
it's no good taking a cold remedy,
因为警察叔叔说吃感冒药后驾车
就等同于服用可卡因后驾车一样
because the police say that's the same as driving
while under the influence of cocaine.
可卡因和板蓝根是两种完全不同的东西
I mean, cocaine and Day Nurse
are different products entirely.
-价格也完全不一样  -完全不同
They're in a different price bracket.
Entirely different.
想说这个的原因是,是从什么时候开始
I bring all this up, OK, because when did it happen
that somebody decided that driving
有人说驾驶变得相当复杂,以至于你不能边开车边做事?
was so unbelievably hard, you can't
do it while doing something else?
比如收听肯・布鲁斯的音乐测验节目,或是打手机
Like listening to Ken Bruce's pop master,
or talking on the phone.
说实话,我想不出什么事我不能一边开车一边做
Honestly, I can't think of anything
that I couldn't do while driving...
除了阅读四开大报纸
apart from reading a broadsheet newspaper.
-读报纸估计不行  -锯木头?
I wouldn't be able to do that. Sawing a piece of wood.
-我可以啊 -你需要..
不不不,你把木头放在两腿之间
I could do that. You'd... No, no,
you put it between your legs.
你还可以踩踏板,并一边锯木头
You can still operate the pedals. You could saw.
缝纽扣? 你需要两只手..
It's like sewing on a button. You need both hands...
我没问题.
-你绝对不行!  -没问题!!
I could do that. You could not! I could!
你知道你不能用锤子来缝按钮吧?!
我知道怎么缝东西
You know you can't sew on a button
with a hammer? I know how to sew.
说到这儿了,你最近听没听说那个事情
While we're on the subject,
did you see that case recently...
警察在高速上拦住了一位女士,因为她一边开车..
a woman who was stopped by the police after they
caught her driving down a motorway while...
..一边"自娱自乐"
causing herself to have pleasure.
我打赌你不能在睡袋里开车
I bet you can't drive in a sleeping bag.
不对,也不一定
Actually, I'm not sure.
我收回. 我觉得你也能在睡袋里开车
I'm going to take that back.
I think you could drive in a sleeping bag.
你不能在睡袋里开车!
-我相信我没问题  -不行!!
You couldn't drive in a sleeping bag.
I bet I could. Can't!
-在睡袋里开车绝对是小事一桩  -没错,就那样
I bet I could drive in a sleeping bag.
Right, you're on!
这周的什么时候,下一集节目之前,我把你带到赛道上
Some time this week, before next week's show,
I'll take you on round the track.
你罩在一个正常的睡袋里,双臂缩进去
You drive in a proper cocoon sleeping bag... Yeah...
我来缝一件衬衫上的纽扣,我们俩赛车
and race me, and I'll sew a button on my shirt.
让我猜猜,我是不是要边开车也边"自娱自乐"一下啊?
Let me guess... I've got to drive whilst
performing an act on myself.
-比赛会很短!  -我们不带你玩了
No. It'd be a short race! We'll leave you out of it.
50码冲刺赛成不成?
Can we make it a 50-yard sprint?!
好的,新闻部分结束,回到影片中去
Right, that is the end of the news,
so let's get back to the action.
如果有贵人多忘事,今天晚上
Tonight, for those of you with very short memories,
我们试着回答一个重要的问题
we are trying to answer an important question...
如果你不想要法拉利458,哪一个是最棒的中置引擎超跑?
which is the best mid-engined supercar
if you don't want a Ferrari 458?
詹姆斯认为是迈凯轮MP4-12C
James says it's the McLaren MP4...12C.
我觉得是兰博基尼Aventador
I say it's the Lamborghini Aventador,
理查德说是Noble M600
and Richard says it's the Noble M600.
目前为止,证明了我的选择是正确的
Yes, and so far, I'm being proved right.
我的极速最快,而且最省油
It achieved the highest top speed
and is the most economical.
不过这些测验结束之后
But having tested those sort of things,
制片人让我们离开赛道,向北驶往罗马
we were then told to leave the test
track and drive north to Rome.
三辆超跑,有爱的天气,驾车穿越意大利
So, three supercars,
lovely weather, drive across Italy,
这能出什么茬子?
what could possibly go wrong(?)
当然,新的一天开始时,哈蒙德显得牛X轰轰..
'Certainly, as the day began, the
rather smug Hammond was very happy,
并开始"自娱自乐"..
'making up his own little games.'
我想来感受一下涡轮的声音,这非常上瘾
I'm going to make some more turbo noise.
It is addictive.
踩下油门,然后松油门
Put the foot down and then lift off. Ooh!
涡轮噪音是给小孩儿玩的,你知道吧?
Turbo noises are sort of for children.
You do know that?
现在我在你旁边开过,并给你个涡轮声. 把车窗摇下来..
Right, I'm going to come alongside and give
you a turbo noise. Drop your window. God...
三, 二, 一
Three, two, one.
这就像是个六岁孩子刚学会纸牌魔术时的那种满足
This is like indulging a six-year-old
child who's learned a simple card trick.
大事不好!
Oh, BLEEP!
很是羞愧,不过我貌似有离合器或是变速箱问题
I hate to say this, but I believe
I have clutch or gearbox issues.
啊呀呀..
Oh, dear.
我不太能理解
I can't understand it myself, cos you know
因为当你看到"莱切斯特制造"这行字时
when you see the legend "made in Leicester"...
-就像是可靠性和质量的代名词  -完全没错
It's a byword for reliability and quality. Absolutely.
莱切斯特还做什么来着?
So what are the other things
that are made in Leicester?
-莱切斯特奶酪?  -附近还有猪肉馅饼卖吧?
Leicestershire cheese?
They make pork pies nearby, don't they?
猪肉馅饼从来都是很可靠的
Yeah. Pork pies are always reliable(!)
你有没有试过反复踩离合器?
Have you tried pumping the clutch, to see if...?
没有,因为连接系统可能也出问题了
Well, no, because the linkage is to cock as well.
很明显,Noble现在寸步难行
'Clearly, the Noble wasn't going anywhere.'
不好意思,让我想想
Let me just think a minute. Sorry.
当我的车出问题的时候
When something goes wrong with my car,
-哈蒙德同学总会..  -帮助你?
Richard Hammond always... helps you.
不,正好相反,他会上他的车溜之大吉
No, the opposite of that.
No, he just gets in his car and drives off.
-没错,我们撤吧  -回见了
You're right. Yes. Let's do that.
Goodbye. Goodbye.
我们把哈蒙德丢在了罗马200英里之外的路边
'We were leaving Hammond 200 miles away from Rome,
这让我们感觉挺羞愧
'and that made us feel quite sorry for him.'
两个月以来,他一直盼着驾驶Noble跑车穿越意大利
For two months, he's been looking
forward to driving his Noble
而现在他只开了30英里!
right across Italy, and he's only gone 30 miles!
行驶里程逐渐增加的同时,我们也更了解自己的座驾了
'As our cars ate up the miles,
we got to know them better.'
天呐,这辆车真是太出色了,真的
Bloody hell, it's good, this. It really is good.
非常的伶俐,也很反应灵敏
It's very clever. It's active, this car.
它没有那种大金属防滚架那种东西
It doesn't have big metal anti-roll bars,
or anything like that.
整车都被它的智脑控制,芯片能够算出每个车轮的职责
Everything is controlled by its brain.
It works out what each wheel is doing.
在你过弯时,每个车轮都能够独立制动
It can even brake an individual wheel as you corner.
以前超跑非常非常难驾驶
In the olden days,
supercars were very, very hard to drive,
而最难驾驶的无疑就是大号的兰博了
and the hardest of them all were the big Lambos.
要想在昆塔奇或是鬼怪里换挡,你需要两只手一起换
Changing gear in a Countach or a Diablo,
you needed two hands.
不过这辆车的感觉就和大众高尔夫一样.
This, though, it feels like a Golf.
I mean, I'm doing, what,
现在我开到时速80英里,车内完全安静
80mph now, and it's almost completely silent.
我能看到前面,也差不多能看到后面
I can see where I'm going.
I can see roughly where I've been.
很值得一提的是
I think it's important to stress at this point,
这辆车的每一个部件都是全新的
every single thing about this car is new.
车身,内饰,引擎,悬架.. 所有都是
Body, interior, engine, suspension. Everything.
整车都在透露着"新"的气息,而且这是能够感受到的
It's brand new, and it feels it.
与此同时,久等了两个半小时之后
'Meanwhile, after a two-and-a-half-hour wait,
来拯救我的盔甲骑士救兵赶到了
'my knight in shining armour finally arrived.'
你好!
Hi!
我说..
Hi...
就是它了
This is the car.
你说句话吧..
Please talk to me.
说个你好也行啊,或者能看见我也行啊..
Please just say hello,
or just... Or see me, even.
马上将驶入一条长长的隧道
Ah, now, there's a big tunnel coming up here.
这时候最不应该干的事就是
The irresponsible thing to do would be to
调整到赛道模式
turn the power train into the track mode
并不必要地减档. 三,二,一,洒家来也!
and change down unnecessarily. Three, two, one, go!
哦~~~! 惊为天人!!
Oh, what a sound!
詹姆斯的车声音相当棒,不过我的车在喷火!
'James's car made a great
noise, but mine was making fire!'
很遗憾哈蒙德不能在这里一起欣赏
It's a shame Hammond isn't here to enjoy the moment.
是吧..
Right...
他需要说那么多话么?
Does he need that many words?
亲娘啊..
Oh, God.
他的手机底部是一条电线
The thing coming off the bottom
of his phone is actually a wire...
连到他的夹克里面,因为那里面全部都是电池
into his jacket, and then that's ALL batteries.
这是我的搭讪表情
That's my open communicative face.
回到六档! 哈哈!!
Oh, back to six! Ha-ha!
我们的日子变得越来越幸福美满
'Our day, meanwhile,
was just getting better and better.'
-这景色真不赖啊!  -确实不可思议!!
That's not a bad view, is it? Marvellous.
才意识到,我正驾驶一辆超级跑车穿越意大利
It's just suddenly hit me,
that I'm driving across Italy in a supercar,
而且我还能看到另一辆超级跑车穿越意大利
and I've got another one to look at!
很久,很久之后..
-晚上好!  -晚上好!
Buona sera! Buona sera!
没错..不知道他说啥
Oh, yeah... No idea.
-说意大利语吗?  -不会..
Parlate Italiano? No.
-英语?  -不会!
-法语?  -不会!
English? No! French? No.
不好,他要打手机..不好..
Oh, no, he's going on the phone.
Oh, no. Oh, no...
又完活一个
Well, that's that, then.
没有最糟,只有更糟..
'Still, could be worse... '
娘的
Oh, dear.
准备盯着鞋看吧
Prepare to look at shoes.
这是我对付欧洲警察的专用表情
This is my special face,
reserved for continental policemen.
离罗马只剩四个小时的路程了
Still, it is under four hours to Rome. Just.
这傻X说啥呢?
拦下我们的原因是
今天是意大利的节假日
The only problem for them is
because today is holiday in Italy.
有趣的是
警察唯一的忧虑是我们在星期日竟然还工作
Interestingly, their only real concern is
that we appear to be working on a Sunday.
因此我们需要个许可证
We need a permit for that.
由此不难看出为啥意大利都快破产了
That's why Italy's nearly bankrupt.
最终,警察们强制我们停止工作
'Eventually, they told us we had to stop working,
于是我们进入罗马享受了一顿可口的晚宴
'so we went into Rome for a lovely dinner.'
有人放屁了
Somebody's farted.
第二天,在罗马城郊的一间修车行里
'The next day, in a workshop in the outskirts of Rome,
我发现了Noble到底出了什么问题
'I found out just what had gone wrong with my Noble.'
这是离合器..这是离合器片
This is the clutch assembly... and
this is the plate and, yeah,
这就是出问题的部件了
that's pretty clearly the component that failed.
只要这个断了,那个就下来了. 它本不该断落的
Once that broke, that came away,
which is not supposed to happen.
不过这个部件好换. Noble虽然不造这种东西
The thing is, this is easily replaceable.
Noble don't make these.
离合器只是Noble买来组装的,
They're bought in... it's a clutch...
but the problem now is,
问题是,由于离合器会在里面呼呼地转
because that was whizzing around inside here,
轴承啊什么的肯定都有损坏
that's damaged bearings and shafts
and all sorts of things.
看看它有没有造成变速箱损坏
What's it done to the gearbox?
詹姆斯和我决定,能帮助哈蒙德最有效的办法是去吃午餐
'James and I decided the best way we
could help Hammond was to go for lunch,
既然是个星期一,我们可以做点工作喽
'and since it was a Monday and we
were allowed to do a bit of work,
我们要比赛谁先到餐厅
看看哪辆车在城市交通中更优秀
'we thought we'd find out which of our cars was
best in traffic by racing to the restaurant.
后到的付账!
'Last one there would pay the bill!'
比赛开始!
Right, let the race begin.
马上这就给兰博带来优势,因为兰博有卫星导航
'Immediately, it was advantage Lambo,
because the Aventador has sat-nav... '
-"路线正在计划中"  -谢了
'Your route is being calculated.' Thank you.
不过在迈凯轮里,卫星导航是个没装的选装配件
'..Whereas, on the McLaren, it's an
option... that hadn't been fitted.'
该死
Bollocks!
我一会儿再看
I'll come back to that.
不过,我的问题也不少
'However, I did have some issues.'
首先是它的宽度
The first problem is width.
它比路虎还要宽5厘米
It's five centimetres wider than a Range Rover.
它差不多和伦敦公交车一样宽
It's very nearly as wide, in fact, as a London bus,
不过最大的问题是它的变速箱
but the biggest problem of them all is the gearbox.
拨片变速箱的赛道表现尚可
Flappy paddle boxes were OK on a track,
在开放的道路上也将就,不过在市区里
they work OK on the open road, but in town,
所有的拨片变速箱都相当垃圾
all of them are useless.
他就在额额额地一路纠结着
It's uh-uh-uh-uh-uh, jerking along, and then,
当你想钻空时,它反应得比蜗牛还慢
when you want to exploit a gap,
it's dim-witted and slow.
这点尤其不好,因为这座城市一天会有117起交通事故
'This was especially bad in a city where
there are 117 road accidents every DAY.'
还没看到一辆车没被撞过的
Haven't actually seen one car yet that isn't dented.
看看那辆!
Look at that one there.
红灯在意大利不代表停车
A red light, but that actually
doesn't mean stop. Not in Italy.
它的意思是,"我们正在试用红灯,一会儿我们会试用绿灯"
It means, "We're trying a red light.
In a minute, we'll try a green one."
它和交通的关系不大
It's not relevant to the actual traffic flow.
那辆车是咋回事..? 天啊!
What happened to that?! Oh, dear.
我们现在要潇潇洒洒地转上亚壁古道
What we're now going to do,
and this is quite cool, really,
也就是罗马的古路
is turn onto the Via Appia, the ancient Roman road,
没有防滚架武装的智能悬挂系统表现很优秀
and the suspension, with its no anti-roll bars and
its intelligent computer, is doing quite well.
而且相当抢眼
Excellently, in fact.
为什么没人去中间的路? 没错,这才是法宝!
Why is nobody using that middle bit?
Yes! That's the ticket!
额,这个,我没想到这条路能这么古罗马
Ah, now, you see, I didn't actually
think it would get quite THAT Roman.
我被一辆Smart超过了!
I'm going to by overtaken by a Smart car!
这个时候,我发现了为什么没人用中间的路
'By this stage, I'd worked out why
no-one was using the middle bit. '
我开上电车轨道了
I've got myself on a railway line.
现在怎么办?
Now what am I going to do?
不好意思,现在我开上了这个..额..
Sorry. Yeah, now I'm basically going down a... Yes.
好么,我现在开到了铁路路基上..
I'm now driving down a railway embankment...
尼诺餐厅,亚壁古道..
Ristorante Nino, Via Appia...
这附近没什么餐厅
你说的没错,它的底盘高度很一般
Yeah, the ground clearance is very poor. OK.
很快,在驶过一条历史之路之后
'Soon, though, after a short drive
through a bit of history... '
不要! 老天爷啊!
No! God Al-bloody-mighty!
我们两个都离目的地很近了
'..We were both near our destination.'
相当接近了
I'm so close.
餐厅在30米之外,就在那里了
Now, the restaurant is coming up in 30 metres.
There it is.
剩下的唯一一项任务就是停车了
'All I had to do now was park.'
那里有个停车位,不过车太宽了
如果我停在这里,整条路就会被我堵上了
It must be that now. It's too wide. You see, if I
park there, I just block the whole street.
天啊,搞笑呢吧?!
Oh, God. No, you're joking.
在这里你怎么停兰博基尼?!
How do you park a Lamborghini here?
这是广场吗? 没错! 我就在正北了
Is that the piazza? I think it is.
I'm right on top of it.
维托里奥街,完全正确!
Via Vittorio. It's correct!
好的,现在找停车位
Right, parking space.
停车停车停车停车
Parking, parking, parking, parking.
用兰博基尼倒车绝对是世界上最"容易"的一件事
It's the easiest thing in the world,
reversing a Lambo.
你只需要从车里出来就行了
You just get out of the car to do it.
能停在那儿吗? 为什么我不能在这儿停呢? 没有停车线
Can I go there? Why can't I go there?
There's no lines.
詹姆斯・梅同志,准备好一败涂地吧
James May, get ready to lose.
-您好?  -您好. 你见过一个长发痴汉么?
-是这位么?
Prego? Prego. Have you seen a very
long-haired man? An idiot? Here.
午餐之后,当然因为是我请客,我们没吃午餐
'After lunch, which I didn't bother
with, because I was paying,
我们决定帮助理查德更有效的方法是去购物
'we decided to help Richard
some more by going shopping.
-然后,我们被惊喜了一下  -那是哈蒙德!
'And then, we got a bit of a surprise.'
That's Hammond.
不过那不是..
No, but it's not...
-你换车了?  -不,这油漆还没干呢
That's a different car. No, no. This is still wet.
别靠在车上,我新刷漆了
Don't lean on it. I painted it.
你还神来之笔把方向盘换位置了?
Then you thought, "I'll put
the steering wheel on this side"(?)
一直都是这一边的,因为你一直从后视镜里看我
It's always been on that side.
You were looking at me in your rear-view mirror.
你这小子换车了!
You have changed cars.
-哈蒙德!  -干嘛?
Hammond? What?
哦,你开玩笑呢吧!! 拜托!
Oh, you're joking! Oh, come on!
这不是我的车,我的是红色的
This isn't my car. Mine's red.
-你还没引起轰动啊!
-春哥好!
You haven't caused a stir.
Buongiorno.
那第一个拖车司机
Did that first delivery driver...
那第一个司机什么话都没说么?
Did that first repair man not say anything? No.
我觉得他都没看见我. 我使劲挥手, "嘿,有人在这儿!"
毫无反应
I don't think he could see me.
"Hello! I'm here." No, nothing.
不管怎样,我想问一句,Noble这么小的公司
Anyway, can we just ask...
how did a tiny little company like Noble
怎么能那么快搞到一辆新车的? 实话实说
get another car out there so quickly?
I'm being serious.
-别说谎  -老实说,他们开过来的
Be serious. Seriously, they drove it.
有位老兄彻夜从工厂开来的
A bloke drove it from the factory, overnight,
从莱切斯特直达罗马
all the way from Leicester to Rome in one hit.
这才是我所说的服务质量呢,
"没问题,先生,我们再送一辆过来就是了"
That's what I call service. "Certainly, sir.
We'll send you another car."
不过这是Noble, 他肯定说的是,
"我们会把留下的唯一的一台车送过去"
But it is Noble... you mean, "We'll
send you THE other car"? Yeah.
我们的节目稍后继续
现在要邀请一位明星驾驶我们的廉价车了
Anyway, we'll pick that up later on. Now, though,
it is time to put a star in our reasonably priced car.
让我列一些歌名,"我不恋爱" "威奇托的架线工" "红色女士"
Let me list some songs. I'm Not In
Love, Wichita Lineman, Lady In Red.
我今晚的的嘉宾从来没唱过那些歌。
My guest tonight hasn't recorded any of those.
那是因为，他来自一个叫“黑眼豆豆”的组织。
That's because he's from an organisation
called the Black Eyed Peas.
女士先生们，欢迎，will点i点am点!
Ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome will.i.am.
近来可好？ 很高兴见到你。
很高兴见到你。
How are you? Good to see you.
Good to see you.
你的电邮地址该怎么写啊!
Your e-mail address must be a nightmare!
will点i点am点@点a点o点l...
(aol：美国在线，著名的因特网服务提供商)
点uk.
我这辈子里从来没见过一个比你还忙的人
I have never met anybody in my entire life
who is apparently as busy as you are,
因为你是一个时装设计师，
because you're a fashion designer,
你为奥巴马工作过；
你是《X战警起源》和《马达加斯加》的主演，
you've worked for Obama, starred
in X-Men Origins and Madagascar,
你为弱势青少年建立了个奖学基金。
you run a scholarship fund for
disadvantaged youngsters,
你是英特尔的创意总监，你开发了智能手机
you're a creative director at Intel,
you developed smartphones,
你为天下人开创了一番新天地，你还自己作词谱曲
produce everyone the world, make your own music,
你是乐队的主唱,为百事可乐,黑莓,本田,杜加迪等公司创作广告曲。
而现在，你创立了一家汽车公司 -没错
什么样的公司？
and you've started a car company.
Yeah. What is it?
告诉我们
Tell us about it.
额，好吧，当我在为英特尔工作的时候，我发现很多手机
So, um, when I was working at Intel,
I found out that a lot of the phones
还有很多日常的东西
and the things that you have
不是你手机上写的那个品牌制作的
aren't really made by the name that's on the phone,
-而是在很多在东南亚那边的公司制作的  -你说那些零部件?
so there's all these companies in Southeast Asia
that make all the equipment. You mean the components?
嗯.然后你把他们装在一起,就像三明治一样,然后产品就出来了。
Yeah. Then you put them together, like a
sandwich, and then you got your product.
然后我坐在我的车里..
Then I got into my car...
我想知道我的宾利的制造成本到底是多少。
I want to know how much it cost to
make this Bentley that I'm driving.
-一辆宾利？  -嗯
大概38便士！
A Bentley? Yeah. About 38 pence!
因为它只是一辆仪表板有些木头的大众车而已。
Right. Cos it's just a Volkswagen
with some wood on the dashboard.
所以，在最近的两年里，我们一直在我的电脑上搞研究设计
So, for the past two years,
we've been tooling, design things on my computer.
我做的第一个改装的名字叫“雷维特”
The first thing I did was a Thundervet,
就是你拿一辆雷鸟和一辆科尔维特混交。。。
where you take a Thunderbird and a vet...
我们这里有一张照片。
We've got a photograph of it.
-嗯，那就是“雷维特”
-那看起来像是一辆50年代的克尔维特
Yeah, that's a Thundervet.
Cos that looks like a '50s vet.
车身上白色的缺口就是典型的50年代科尔维特风格
The white slash is '50s vet, but there's
-还有一些雷鸟的东西混杂在一起？ -恩
some Thunderbird in there, as well? Yeah.
额，这个凹槽和其他一些东西。
这些不是白色边的轮胎。
So, the groove and stuff. And those
wheels aren't white-wall tyres.
那是白边轮毂，里面是五幅式的。
That's a white-wall rim,
with the five-spoke inside of it.
噢，那其实是一个轮毂？
Oh, that's the actual rim?
-没错  -简直太漂亮了。这货搭载什么引擎了？
Yeah. That's fantastic. So, what engine has it got?
它搭载一个超大号的科尔维特引擎。
That has a super-sized
Corvette engine in it.
那么你现在设计你自己的车了没？
就是自己设计的车身的车。
And have you designed your own
car now, with its own body?
有,这只是一个试验品,来试验我们究竟能干什么
Yes. So, that was just, you know,
let's test what we can do with this.
以那车作为标准，我们自己打造一辆车。
From there, we go on to something
that we built from scratch.
-我想我们也有那车的照片  -这就是IAMAUTO 88
I think we've got a picture of it, as well.
IAMAUTO 88.
那真像一台老玛莎拉蒂总裁，只不过这是两门的。
It's a bit like an old Maserati
Quattroporte, except it's two-door.
-而且那是加州制造的?  -那是在我出生的贫民窟那里制造的
-为什么？真的？
And that's made in California? That's made down
in the ghetto that I'm from. Why...? Really?
我的人生目标是，我要制作音乐，那样我就可以照顾我妈
Yeah. My whole thing was, "I'm going to
make music so I can take care of my mom,
然后将我全家搬离贫民窟。
"and move my family out the ghetto."
如果那是我的目标，我就不会停。
So, if that's what I want to do,
then it's going to keep me going,
我不会有后退这个选项
so there's no "no" for an answer.
然后，我现在已经完成这个目标了
我家里的所有人。。。
So, now that I've done that, and
every single person in my family...
堂兄弟，叔伯，侄女
和侄子。。。全都搬离贫民窟了，
cousins, uncles, nieces
and nephews... are out the ghetto,
我想回到我的贫民窟，然后创立一家汽车公司。
I want to go back to my ghetto
and build a car company.
我们一直都在抱怨欠发展地区拖了我们的后腿，
We all complain about underdeveloped communities,
不过要谁来发展他们呢?
but who are the developers in the first place?
所以我想,“我已经很烦抱怨和指责神马的了。”
So, I was like, "I'm tired of
complaining and pointing fingers.
为什么我自己不想清楚，扪心自问，
"Why don't I aim that finger to me and say,
哥们，你有什么办法能改变你的贫民窟家乡？
"'Hey, what are you doing to change
the ghetto you're from?'"
你是我邀请的嘉宾里面最鼓舞人生志向的嘉宾之一了
Do you know, you're one of the most inspiring people
we've ever had sitting in that sofa.
毫无疑问吧?
He is, though, isn't he?
如果每个人都这样想，我们的经济发展也会飞天了！
If everybody thought like that,
we'd have 1.65% growth as well!
说说你的汽车史吧
Um, can we just go into your car history?
从什么时候开始的？你的第一辆车是什么？
Where did it begin? What was your first car?
在我17岁的时候,我给自己买了一辆..
So, I got a record deal when I was
17 and I bought myself...
因为我一直想要辆法拉利,或者德罗宁
（电影《回到未来》的时光机车型）
cos I always wanted a Ferrari or a DeLorean.
那是我最喜欢的车。但我买不起。。。
Those were my favourite cars.
I couldn't afford those,
所以我买了辆穷逼中的法拉利，菲罗。
so I got the poor man's Ferrari, which is a Fiero.
额，那的确挺穷逼的。那是穷逼中的MR2。
Yeah, that's really poor.
That's even the poor man's MR2.
我那辆是黄色的。
I had a yellow one.
中置引擎，所以看起来也像是法拉利
Mid-engine, so it was kind of like a Ferrari
如果你在5英里之外外眯着眼看
if you were standing five miles away and squinting!
然后,我的邻居皮尔林出卖了我。
And then my next-door neighbour Pearleen snitched.
她告诉我妈，
“(美国黑人口音)噢，黛布拉阿姨，小威威买了一辆车哦。”
She told my mom,
"Ooh, Debra, Willy got himself a new car."
然后我妈叫我进屋里。
And then my mom calls me in the house.
“(继续口音)孩子，屁股放椅子上。”
"Boy, sit your butt down on this couch."
"(继续口音)妈，干嘛？"
"你哪来的权利买那傻X车?"
"What, Momma?
"You got no business buying yourself no G-damn car.
"但是.."
"Yeah, but..."
"但是你个头。给我那傻X钥匙。"
"No but nothing. Gimme them damn keys."
嗯，她没收了我的车。
So she confiscated my car.
然后在我20岁以前都不能开车。
So then I couldn't drive until I was 20.
就放在那里不动？一辆2000美金的车楞放了三年？
So it just sat there? A 2,000...Car. For three years?
三年来一直放在那里。
For three years it sat there.
能开它的20岁前,每一天我都是度日如年
I couldn't wait till I was 20, then I could drive it.
黑眼豆豆..你卖了多少张唱片？几百万吧
Black Eyed Peas... how many records
have you sold? Millions.
-根据现有的数据，4000多万。
-4000多万？
To date, 40 something million records. 40 million?
太强悍了,而且你还有个..
It is massive. And you've got...
没错，4000万。
Yeah! 40 million.
还有你现在新出了个独唱的专辑？
And you've now got a solo album out.
而且它叫"两横两竖,威尔力量"
And it's called Squiggle Squiggle #willpower.
-不，那是个井字号,"#威尔力量"
-那么是"井字号,威尔力量"
No, it's just #willpower. #willpower.
不过那两横两竖..噢,是井字号!
There are squiggles.
Oh, it's a hash!
我还以为那是一个印刷错误呢
I just thought it was like a misprint. No, no.
-你有没有被一个比我更老的人采访过？
-额，这个..没有..
Have you ever been interviewed by
somebody more old than me? Um... no...
现在,你来到这儿..看着你的手套,还以为是来打高尔夫
不过不是来打高尔夫的
Now, you came down here, obviously... well, looking at
your gloves, to play golf, but, um, it isn't a Golf.
不，不。我戴这些不包住手指的手套的原因是
No, no. The reason I have fingerless gloves is
哥有很多触摸屏设备
because I got touchscreen technology devices,
所以你最不愿意发生的事情就是，
你带着手套,突然手机响了..
so last thing you want is, in the cold,
I have to go, "My phone is ringing..."
不过你还可以买那种上面有指纹的手套
戴上它,你很容易就能..我就有一双
No, cos you can buy gloves that have got
fingerprint things, so wearing... I've got a pair.
它们太老土了。
They're not fashion.
那是世界上最丑的手套。
There you go! They're the ugliest
gloves in the world.
我承认，它们看上去挺穷逼的。
They look pretty poor, I admit.
我记得你坚持要开一辆自动挡的车,拒绝了手动挡
You insisted, I believe, in driving
the automatic car, rather than the stick-shift.
那么你自我感觉怎么样？
Yeah. So, how did it go out there?
我觉得我干得不错,如果从各种冲出赛道的水平来评价的话
I think I did pretty good,
if you judge me on spinning.
额，好吧，谁要看威哥的打滑？
Well, now, who would like to see some of Will's spins?
我们精心挑选了一些，看看吧。
We have a selection. Let's have a look.
没错,倒数第二个弯道
Yes, there we go. Second-to-last corner.
士兵突击..他控制住了..没控制住..哎呀呀..
Bold as brass. He's held it...
No, he hasn't! Ooh!
那是一个鱼尾打滑..于是又来了一次
That's a tank-slapper, that one was.
Yeah. Here we go again.
转来转去！
Spinny!
为什么我们在鼓掌？全是各种失败镜头。
Why are we applauding? Those were mistakes.
你应该弄一个漂移奖神马的。。。
You probably want to have a different spin award...
谁要看最终的跑圈？
Who would like to see the finished lap?
好吧，坐稳咯。
Let's play the tape. Here we go.
自动挡都能让轮胎空转,真是技术活
Needs to spin with an automatic box.
Like to see it!
上吧
Right, here we go.
第一弯。像很多F1车手一样，走线很宽。
Here's the first corner.
Wide line, like a Formula 1 driver.
轮胎在嚎叫。。。尽管地面湿滑！
Tyre squeal... even in the wet!
噢，很利落。相当利落啊。
Oh, that's nicely done. That was nicely done.
刹车。。。
Brake...
寡言老男人
A man of few words.
走线很顺,很好的通过了那弯道。
That's nice and smooth through there.
很好的宽走线，这样能让动力完全输出。
Good wide lines, so you
can get the power down.
来到锤头弯
And up to the Hammerhead.
在这里呀么重刹车..
# Brake hard, brake here... #
-你在唱歌啊？ -让我集中注意力神马的。
Were you singing? To keep myself focused and stuff.
我有点紧张。。。
I was getting kinda nervous.
-白线儿，白线儿。。。
-很漂亮。
# The line and the lines... #
It's good.
听听这C一撇D的引擎声
C apostrophe D now. Listen to that engine.
我勒个去，传说中的运动声音。
Wow! That's a sporty noise.
快跑啊,你个2B青年专用车！
Go! Stupid car!
看似不错。。。
Looking good through there...
喔，扬起了点刚刚冲出赛道挂上的尘土。
Oh, there's a bit of dirt
from an earlier spin coming out.
通过轮胎墙。
Through the tyres.
通过倒数第二个弯，会有问题么？
Are we going to get through the
second-to-last without a problem?
切弯切得恰到好处! 到达甘邦弯..
That was cut perfectly. And Gambon...
保持紧凑的走线..当我没说
Keep it in tight... All right, don't.
冲过终点线！
And there we are! And across the line!
你开的是自动挡，自然会慢点
So... Now, you're driving the automatic,
so that's slower, obviously,
而且还在下雨，所以我们不要期望太高
and it's raining, so we're not looking
for a particularly fast time.
不过呢..其实我在想，
Um... but... I'm trying to think, actually.
自动挡嘉宾。。。目前为止我们只有两个。
Automatic drivers... we've only had
two so far in this car.
他们是约翰・普雷斯科特(英国前首相)。
They are John Prescott.
-你不认识他吧？ -嗯。
You don't know John Prescott? Hmm.
他也是时装设计师。
He's a fashion designer.
还有艾利斯・库柏(摇滚乐歌手)
And Alice Cooper. OK?
-这两个是唯一的自动挡嘉宾，大概都在1:56左右
-而且都是湿圈。
Those are the only automatics, and
they're both 1.56. And they're wet.
嗯，都是湿的，都是自动挡。
Oh, yeah. Both had wet days,
both driving automatics.
都在1分56秒区域。
Both in the 1.56.3 region.
will点i点am点， 你的成绩是一分..
will.i.am., you did it in 1...
四十..
40...
九秒四
9.4.
嗯，湿圈和自动挡。
So, you get wet and auto,
这个圈速是湿+自动里面最快的！
and that's the fastest we've ever had
in that car in those conditions! Yay!
你排在..这里
You are... there.
在埃塞克斯的23岁的皮塔之上,乔纳森・罗斯之下
So, above Peta, 23, from Essex... Below Jonathan Ross.
-Stig的教授水平不赖啊!  -没错
Stig did a good thing, then. Oh, yeah.
那单圈令人印象深刻,你真正竭尽了全力
That was impressive, and you were trying.
能邀请你来既鼓舞人的意志,又是巨大的愉悦
It has been genuinely inspirational
having you here, and an enormous pleasure.
女士们先生们,欢送威廉!
Ladies and gentlemen, will.i.am! Thank you!
好的,回到我们的超级跑车路测
Right, now, we must get back to our big supercar test.
目前为止,我们已经看到我的Noble是最快的,最省油的
So far, we've established that my Noble
is the fastest and the most economical.
-也是最不可靠的  -玩去..
The most unreliable. Yes, funny.
我们也看到了我的迈凯轮在市区表现最佳
We've also established that
the McLaren is the best around town,
-而杰里米的兰博大白痴还什么都没赢呢 -什么都没赢!
and that Jeremy's big, idiotic Lamborghini
hasn't actually won anything. Nothing! Zero.
零. 各种鸭蛋各种圈...
Hmm. Nil. Zilch. Rien. Nowt.
-零的平方根  -什么都没赢,这个我们有目共睹
The square root of Jack.
Nothing... we've established that!
让我们继续吧,现在要放第三段
Let's move on,
because it's time now for part three,
其中我们面临着我们做过的最危险的事
in which we three must face the most
dangerous thing we've ever done.
在我们为与命运女神的约会一路向北时
'As we headed north to our date with destiny,
我们开始把我们的车与终极擂主进行比较
'we started to think about how
our cars compare to the daddy.'
三天前,如果你问我
Three days ago, if you'd said to me,
"你想要一辆Aventador还是法拉利458?"
"Which would you rather have,
an Aventador or Ferrari 458?"
我肯定会选法拉利,因为那是明智之选
I would have said, "The Ferrari."
I mean, it's the obvious choice.
不过如果你现在问我,我会选这个
But now... No, I'd have this.
我清楚法拉利458是绝对的技术结晶,它的外形也令人窒息
I know a Ferrari 458 is just a technical
masterpiece and it looks wonderful,
不过这辆车有一些法拉利不具备的东西
but this has got something the Ferrari doesn't have.
它有个性
It has... It has a character.
这就像一条愚蠢的橙色的狗
It's like a big, daft orange dog!
人人都爱橙色大蠢狗!
Everybody wants a big, daft orange dog!
它完全赢得了我的心. 它不仅是这三辆中最棒的
It's won me over. Completely.
It's not just the best car here.
它比法拉利458还要更胜一筹
It's better than the Ferrari 458.
对我来说,它是世界上最棒的几辆车之一. 我爱上它了
For me, it's one of the best cars in
the world now. I absolutely love it.
它就像一辆赛车,不过没有赛车的不实用和不舒适
It feels like a race car but without
the impracticality and discomfort.
的确,它的制造商是英国一个没人听说过的厂子
But, yes, they're a small make in the
UK that nobody has ever heard of.
不过帕加尼的风之子也是诞生于一个没人听说过的厂子
Well, at one time, so was Mr Pagani, making his Zonda.
已经有两票反对法拉利了. 那么詹姆斯怎么想?
So, that's two votes against the Ferrari.
But what about James?
这辆车很棒,我越来越喜欢它
This is brilliant.
I'm really, really growing to like it,
不要忘了它比法拉利458要便宜3万5千英镑
and let's not forget it's ￡35,000
or so cheaper than the Ferrari 458.
那可是不少的一笔钱
And that is a huge amount of money.
不过他还是..我也不知道
But there's still... I don't know.
我感觉法拉利的换挡更干脆
The Ferrari, I think the gear change
feels a bit crisper,
整车的一切都更清晰
and everything feels a little better defined, somehow.
可能这就是无法形容出来的激情吧
It's the fizz, I'm afraid.
I can't explain it. I just...
法拉利能给我带来更多的激情
The Ferrari still gives me more fizz.
你已经到达目的地
'You have reached your destination.'
事实证明,目的地是一条赛道
'The destination turned out to be a racetrack...
它的名叫伊莫拉
'called Imola...
小小休整之后
'..where, after a quick change,
我们到维修区接受挑战
'we were told to report to the pits for a challenge.'
你们现在要在赛道上跑圈,并尝试击败法拉利458的圈速
"You will now lap the circuit, attempting
to beat the time set by a Ferrari 458."
-谁来开458呢?  -上面说不是Stig
Who's driving a 458?
It says here he's not The Stig.
而是Stig的意大利表兄
But he is The Stig's Italian cousin!
这是色迷迷Stig么?
It's "Bunga-Bunga" Stig.
他都干嘛了?
What's he been doing?!
扑克牌
Cards.
不管他都干嘛了
'Whatever it was he'd been doing,
显然他驾驶的能量还是够的
'he plainly still had
plenty of energy left for driving.
并跑出了一个吓人的时间 - 1分56秒6
'And posted a daunting time of 1.56.6.
在尝试击败这个时间之前
'Before trying to beat that,
we thought it best to spend
我们觉得开着车在赛道上试试手还是很有必要的
'a little time learning how our cars
behaved on a proper racetrack.'
赛道模式的换挡太野蛮了
That gear change in track mode is absolutely savage.
上那个路肩!
Ride that kerb!
四轮驱动系统简直令人窒息
Four-wheel drive system is breathtaking.
动力在不断地改变方向,向前,向后,向左,向右
The power is constantly moving around... front, back,
你总是有足够的抓地力
side to side... so you've always
got the grip you need.
好处是,我的刹车是碳纤维的,所以不会过热
The good thing is, I have carbon
brakes which will not fade.
可怜鼹鼠同学的刹车是钢制的,会过热
Poor old Hammond has got steel brakes, which will.
注意力集中,要顺滑
Focus. Smoothness.
这样的跑车没有驾驶辅助和计算机,只有你和这台机器
A car like this, with no driver aids, no computers
messing about, it's just you and the car.
唯一的机会就是出弯之后
The only chance I stand here is to
get it out of the corners
能够充分利用它的动力
in such a shape that I can use that power.
当然,迈凯轮有一大堆的驾驶辅助系统
Of course, the McLaren does have a lot of driver aids,
不过"方向感船长"有更重要的事情来担心
but Captain Sense Of Direction had
more important things on this mind.
这弯怎么过来着? 想不起来了
What's this one? I can't remember.
这是我不需要刹车的弯角
This is the bit where I don't have to brake...
如果我没记错的话..
If I can remember this bit...
一天收工之后,我们了解了赛道,了解了我们的跑车
At the end of the day, we knew
the circuit and we knew our cars.
不过我们一点自信心都没有
But still, we were not feeling
even remotely confident,
因为这里是伊莫拉
because this is Imola...
这个星球上最危险的几条赛道之一
one of the most dangerous tracks on Earth.
它狭窄高速,并被毫无怜悯心的树林和护墙所包围
It's narrow, fast and ringed with
unforgiving walls and trees.
吉列・维伦纽夫
Gilles Villeneuve,
杰哈德・伯格
Gerhard Berger,
尼尔森・皮奎特, 里卡多・帕特里塞, 鲁本・巴里切罗..
Nelson Piquet, Riccardo Patrese,
Rubens Barrichello...
历史上,这条赛道的每一个弯角都结果了一些大人物的赛车
at some point in history, every corner
here has claimed the ego of a big name.
而某些赛道结果了比赛车更珍贵的东西..
And some corners have claimed even more than that.
1994年塞纳丧命之后
After Senna's death in 1994,
赛道作出调整,降低了赛车的速度
changes were made to the track to slow the cars down,
不过尽管如此,如果我们想击败那台法拉利
but even so, if we were going to beat that Ferrari,
转过一号弯的时速仍然能达到200英里
we would still be going through the
first bend at nearly 200mph.
所以,那一天晚上,我们每个人都与自己的车独处了一小会
So, that night, each of us spent a little
time alone with the cars we'd be using.
你就是尤文图斯队
YOU are Juventus.
明天你将对阵沃金城和莱切斯特城
And tomorrow, you're taking on
Woking Town and Leicester City.
全英格兰的球迷都想让他们赢,因为他们不占上风
And everybody in England is going to want
them to win,because they're the underdogs.
不过不要担心
But don't you worry.
我们虽然还未赢得一项挑战
We haven't won a single challenge yet,
不过明天..就变了
but tomorrow... that will change.
这场战斗,你没有用复杂的智能芯片武装到牙齿
You're not going into battle armed with
a sophisticated computer and wizardry,
你也没有敏捷的悬挂和四轮驱动,你只有一台引擎
clever suspension, four-wheel drive.
You're just going in with an engine.
用古老的方式战斗
Doing it the old-fashioned way.
不管你占不占上风,我知道你现在已是破釜沉舟
Underdog or not, I know you've got it in you now.
我太希望我们赢得胜利了
I'd love us to win.
记住,当我们驶上赛道
Just remember, as we're going round and
当你无限纠结于我的杯具换挡
you're despairing of my terrible gear changes
以及我的杯具过弯等等等等时
and my bad apexes, and things,
记住,你来自于迈凯轮,你有着这些车里面最棒的赛车血统
you're made by McLaren.
You've got the best race pedigree.
你有敏捷的悬挂
You've got clever suspension,
没有防滚架,你还有一台电脑
you've got no roll bars, you've got a computer,
你可以为我制动车轮,你都可以自己完成很多任务
you can brake the wheel for me,
you can virtually do it by yourself.
你只需要娱乐我一下,记住我龟速船长的称号
All you have to do is humour me a bit,
and remember that I'm Captain Slow.
或者是意大利人们给我的"蜗牛先生"的美名
Or Mr Slowly, as the Italians call me.
第二天早上
'The next morning,
我们开始在赛道上冒险,并尝试击败Stig的1分56秒6的成绩
'we ventured onto this terrifying track
to try and beat The Stig's 1.56.6.'
天啊,这真是快!
God, this is quick!
妈呀!!
Oh, my giddy aunt!
我出赛道了!
I'm off the road!
重回赛道上了!
I'm on it again!
天啊,在这里开得更快了
My God, I'm faster here.
太凶险了. 我靠
This is outrageous. Oh, BLEEP.
不要被理智束缚,别当胆小鬼!
Now, faster than you think. Don't be a wimp.
啊!! 有可能被吓尿了
Agh! A bit of wee may be coming out!
别太早刹车,别太早刹车. 现在刹车!
Don't brake too early. Don't brake too early. Now!
强多了
Better.
不寻常的是,这个挑战我们很在乎
'Unusually, we were all taking this
challenge very seriously... '
-2分零5秒4, 2分零4秒9.  -2分零2秒整
-哦,不,我才开到2分零7秒
2:05.4, 2:04.9. Oh, no. I'm still on 2.07.
不过我们清楚,要想击败法拉利
'..But we knew we'd have to try even harder
我们还要更加努力
if we were going to beat that Ferrari.'
加油啊,梅,你个二愣子! 前进!
Right, come on, May, you blithering idiot. Avanti.
漂亮!
Good!
入弯..刹车!
In... Braking down.
狠一点!
Get cocky!
赛道还在,别松懈!
The track WILL be there. Keep it in!
妙!
Yes!
我现在要发疯一点了
I'm going a bit mental here, now.
刹车..有点糟糕
Brake... Ooh, that's messy.
我要进五档,我要TM敢开多快开多快
I'm going to go for 5th. I'm going to take
as much through here as I bloody dare. Oh!
加油!
Come on!
时速290公里
290...
刹车失灵了,哇,刹车过热了
OK, brakes have gone. Whoa.
Failure from the brakes.
在我的刹车冷却,哈蒙德把砂石清理出去之后
After my brakes had cooled,
and Hammond had emptied his car of gravel,
我们重上赛道开始击败458的最后一次尝试
we went back out for
one final attempt to beat the 458.
兰博的背水一战了! 来了,加油!!
And the Lambo is only... Here we go! Come on!
最后一次了,我为了莱切斯特的荣誉而战!
OK, this is it. I'm doing this one for Leicester!
给力啊!
Right, Beans!
这就对了!
That's it!
现在刹车!
And now brake!
困难的部分已经过去了!
I've done the difficult bit!
能过去,一定能过去
It will go round, it WILL.
加油!
Come on!
刹车..
And brake...
重拾动力越快越好. 现在,现在!! 动力!!!
And back on the power as soon
as you can. Now. NOW! NOW! Power!
保持右边,保持右边..入弯!
Stay right, stay right, stay right!
Stay right, now!
加速加速! 加油!
Stretch it, stretch it! Come on! Come on!
加油加油!!
Come on! Come on!
没问题的! 给力!!
You can do it! Come on!
-那看起来和实际上一样吓人  -的确很恐怖
That looked as scary as it was. Yes, it was scary.
就是那可感觉的"我的妈呀"时刻
It's that palpable sense of, "Oh, my God!"
必须要说,在驶过维修区的大直路上,赛道不是笔直的
Because I have to say, as you go past
the pits, the track is not straight,
赛道是有弯的,不过你不敢松油门
it's a curve, and you daren't lift off,
because the crews,
因为摄像组能够听到引擎的声音改变
所以你不得不死死地保持踩着油门
they can hear the engine note change, so
you have to keep your foot hard down.
-很恐怖的  -时速是200英里多..?
-超过了200英里
It was terrifying.
It is 200 and...? Over 200.
我们三个的瞬时时速都超过了F1赛车在那一段的速度
All three of us doing over 200, and that's faster
than a Formula 1 car, was going through there.
F1只能开到时速180英里左右
They could only do about 180.
我什么都不知道,因为我的眼睛闭的死死的
I don't know, because I had my eyes shut.
太吓人了
It was terrifying.
不管怎样,现在要揭晓我们三个的最快圈速了
Anyway, it is time now to reveal who
was the fastest of the three of us.
-哈蒙德?  -我的圈速是2分零3秒3
Richard Hammond? I did it
in 2 minutes and 3.3 seconds.
已经到达我的极限了
That's the best I could do.
"蜗牛先生"?
Mr Slowly?
2分零6秒4
2 minutes 6.4.
-太好了!  -你呢?
Yes! And you?
-这时候不显得装X可有点难度..  -天啊..
It's so difficult not to look
smug at this point. Oh, God!
-不管用的  -1分59秒1!
It's not working.
1... Ooh! ..59.1.
掩饰不了的
You're not pulling it off.
-不管用  -的确不行,算了吧
It's not working. It isn't. No, I'll forget it.
那么把问题搞清楚. 你开得很漂亮
Let me just straighten this out, OK? Well done.
我们每人都把车发挥到了极限,不过还是没能击败法拉利
We gave it everything, each of us,
and we didn't beat the Ferrari. No.
慢着,这没有什么关系
Hang on. That's not strictly relevant,
这整个挑战的重点就是,如果你不想要法拉利
because the point of this was to see which car
你应该选择哪一台车
you should have IF you didn't want a Ferrari.
-没错,应该选兰博  -才不是!
-就是兰博嘛!
Yes, it's the Lambo. No. It isn't. It IS the Lambo.
我承认,这不是一辆完美的赛道用车
I admit, it's not a brilliant track car,
在纳多赛道,它的轮胎必须要换,这是个麻烦事
because at Nardo, it's tyres had to be changed,
it was a problem there.
不知怎么它又把碳刹车烧废了
And somehow it boiled its carbon brake,
no idea how it did that.
不过它就是条橙色的大蠢狗,排气管还会喷蓝色火焰
But it IS a big, daft orange dog, AND
blue stuff comes out of the exhaust.
听好,在那一天,Noble教会我的驾驶技术
No. Look, that Noble taught me more
about driving in that one day
比其它任何一辆车教会我的都多
than any other car has ever taught me.
-这是纯粹的驾驶感觉  -稍安勿躁
It's about the real undiluted experience. Silence.
迈凯轮是相比终极战车458最接近的一辆车
The McLaren is the closest thing
to the 458, which is the best,
所以迈凯轮是这三辆车中最棒的
therefore the McLaren is the best car here.
-它的排气管会喷蓝色火焰吗?  -没有
Does blue stuff come out of the exhaust? No.
-那不就完了  -问题是,我们还是不能达成共识
Exactly. Well, there you are.
The thing is, we can't agree.
其实我们永远也不能达成共识
And actually, we never will. No.
以这个猛料作为结尾,节目结束的时间到了
非常感谢大家的收看
And on that bombshell, it is time to
end. Thanks very much for watching.
我们下周见! 晚安!
See you next week. Good night!
Top Gear 第18季 第1集
字幕制作: 百度TopGear吧 derekdi 清野过客 吃烧饼不掉芝麻
水平有限 难免有误 敬请谅解